Rodrigo Leles

Senior Product Designer

rodrigoleles.com dribbble.com/rodrigoleles instagram.com/rodrigo_leles

São Paulo, Brazil contato@rodrigoleles.com +55 11 996 209 728

I have been building digital products and brands with focus on crafting neat user experiences for +15 years. Currently working as a freelancer with various agencies, startups, companies and people all over the world.

Experience

Senior Product Designer at IFTTT • Mar 2021 - Jul 2024

IFTTT is a leading internet connectivity platform providing connectivity solutions to the world's most innovative brands, helping 22 million people discover and create useful agents. Some highlights of our design work:

- Kicked-off Al integrations by allowing users to use LLMs when creating automations.
- A full revamp of product's design system, contributing for faster development processes and more consistent user experience.
- 10% increase on engagement on website call to actions with positive impact on MRR.

Head of Design at Cooklist • Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Cooklist has an amazing mission: Make people eat intelligently. My role was not only define the UX vision and strategy but create the end-to-end customer experience and UI at both the macro and micro interaction level:

- Implemented a user research routine, actively talking to real users to gather data about our assumptions to identify and measure critical product KPIs.
- Delivered a significant boost in user retention and 4.8 App Store rating, with more than 9k reviews.
- We won the 2018's Techstars Acceleration program.

UX Lead at 99 • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

99 is the largest Brazilian ride hailing service, one of the largest startup in Latin America and the first Brazilian unicorn. My the role was to help the safety squad and there:

- Ideated, tested and delivered more than 50 safety focused features for before, during and after the ride experience for drivers and passangers.
- Led a safety for women program, engaging coworkers to learn about empathy and how a simple digital feature can impact qualitative metrics.

UX Designer at Anheuser-Busch InBev • Jul 2015 - Aug 2017

As part of Anheuser-Busch InBev Disrupt Growth Office we led a global brand and UI initiative for a handfull digital experiments, like the one that inspired Zé Delivery: LATAM's leading beverage delivery app:

- Created an A/B testing center of excellence.
- Championed the management of designers across Brazil, Mexico, Argentina, and the Dominican Republic, fostering collaboration that accelerated project timelines by 20% and enhanced design consistency across all platforms.

Digital Art Director at Artplan • Oct 2014 - Jul 2015

As the Senior Art Director, my role consisted in creating and developing ideas in a multiplatform format for integrated campaigns. Joined projects for clients as Amil, Amanco, Estácio, Itaipava, Etna, Niely, Melitta, Caixa, Rock in Rio and others.

Education

Interview Workshop: Get the Most out of Your Interviewees • 2018 Ivan Mizansuk (online)

Intensive Art Direction • 2017 Escola CUCA

Design, Aesthetics and Art Direction • 2016 Saulo Milleti

Digital Design Bachelor • 2006 - 2010 Anhembi Morumbi University

Certifications

The Webflow Masterclass • 2019 Flux Academy (Teachable)

The 10k Website Process • 2020 Flux Academy (Teachable)

UX Design On Demand • 2016 General Assembly

Lean Six Sigma White Belt • 2016 Anheuser-Busch InBev